SATHISH BABU.G

↑Hyderabad

SUMMARY

Results-oriented IT professional with over 5 years of experience. Having good Knowledge on developing web Applications using technologies like Java, Spring, Spring-Boot with Micro services in CI/CD with Jenkins, Cloud PCF. Developed, Updated and maintained the web applications based on the business requirement thoroughly and delivered the product outcome in specified timeline.

EDUCATION

M Tech | Vellore Institute of Technology (Vellore)

June 2014- Apr 2016

Major: Structural Engineering

> CGPA: 8.08

B Tech | Chaitanya Engineering College (Visakhapatnam)

May 2010- Jun 2014

Major: Civil Engineering ➤ PERCENTAGE :70.8%

Work Experience:

JAVA DEVELOPER Jun 2018 - Till Date

SRIROY TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD

Hyderabad

- > Hands on experience in web application development using Java and J2EE Technologies, RESTful web Services. created multiple screens and used Spring-Boot as Backend in Agile Methodology.
- Experience on TDD (Test Driven Development), JUnit, Git, SVN, Maven, Kibana.
- ➤ Good experience in developing and designing web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.
- ➤ Have good knowledge on CI/CD using Jenkins, cloud is PCF.
- Good working experience with source code versioning tools such as SVN & Git.
- > Good experience interacting with Business Analysts, developers, technical support and help them in base line the required specifications.
- Analysed requirements, designed and develop the code based on the business need

ASSISTANT SYSTEM ENGINEER

June 2016 – May 2017

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES (TCS)

NSE (Mumbai)

- > Environment creation and handling, EOD application, generation and presentation of daily, weekly and monthly reports on work progress.
- Performed system based testing by using Linux
- Provided UAT support and solved UAT defects and issues
- Created utility to automate the daily operational activities by using Shell Scripting.

Projects:

LIBRARY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Client : Halifax Library (Canada)

Roles and Responsibilities : Developed this application using spring-boot

Team Size : 6

Description:

This project is all about Managing the library Data information in the application. We have user as Admin, who is responsible to add/view/delete books, issue and view issued books. The admin is authenticated with the username and password. Once the Admin logs in the system. The menu page opens whether to add/view/delete/issue/view issue books. As, per the request the admin performs the task and manages the system. And the added books will be visible in the user screen. Whoever gives the comments/suggestion/questions will be visible to the admin and will respond to the customer.

CUSTOMER COMPLAINT MODULE

Client : Versa Bank (Canada)

Roles and Responsibilities : Developed this application using Java

Team Size : 7

Description:

This project is for used for handling the customer complaint request. The end customers raise complaints when they face any issue with accessing the application/or anything that they are not able to get it. We take the requests and route them to the specific teams. We have large team sets for different departments and they will be routed to the concerned team. We have batch jobs running at the end of the day to see how many complaints were raised. And analysis how many are completed, pending, or blocked.

TECHNOLOGY STACK

Operating Systems	Windows, Unix & Linux
Languages & Scripting	Java & Shell Scripting
Technologies	Oops, Design Patterns, SOAP, REST, Hibernate, JPA, Spring, Spring Boot,
	Spring Batch, Spring Security, Spring AOP, JUnit,Log4J
Cloud	PCF & AWS
Devops Tools	Jenkins, Docker
UI	HTML, CSS, Java Script
Version Control	SVN, Git, Bitbucket
Database	Oracle, SQL Server
Web Servers	Tomcat, Web Sphere, Web Logic
IDE	Eclipse, IntelliJ